Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Where are you now?
أين أنت الآن؟
Nearby. Five minutes.
قريب. خمس دقائق.
You pulled two all-nighters.
لقد سهرت ليلتين كاملتين.
You must be exhausted.
لا بد أنك مرهق.
In our line of work,
في مجال عملنا،
who doesn't stay up late?
من لا يسهر حتى وقت متأخر؟
I'm used to it.
لقد اعتدت على ذلك.
Once the proposal is approved,
بمجرد الموافقة على الاقتراح،
I'll catch up on beauty sleep.
سألحق بنوم الجمال.
Don't put too much pressure on yourself.
لا تضع الكثير من الضغط على نفسك.
Just perform as you normally do.
فقط قم بالأداء كما تفعل عادةً.
With your ability, you've got this.
بفضل قدراتك، يمكنك تحقيق ذلك.
By the way, I sent you Tongchen's info.
بالمناسبة، لقد أرسلت لك معلومات تونغتشين.
Take a look.
خذ نظرة.
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Can you hear me?
أيمكنك سماعي؟
♪The possibility inside the impossible♪
♪الاحتمال داخل المستحيل♪
♪Is still hiding in a parallel universe♪
♪لا يزال مختبئًا في عالم موازٍ♪
♪I don't have the talent for happiness♪
♪ليس لدي موهبة السعادة♪
♪I can only admit it♪
♪لا أستطيع إلا أن أعترف بذلك♪
♪There must be some kind of possibility in my imagination♪
♪لا بد أن يكون هناك نوع من الاحتمال في خيالي♪
♪That will crush all impossibilities into dust♪
♪هذا سوف يسحق كل المستحيلات إلى غبار♪
♪Even if they mock my delusion and slowness♪
♪حتى لو سخروا من وهمي وبطئي♪
♪My foolishness♪
♪حماقتي♪
=Sniper Butterfly=
=فراشة القناص=
(Adapted from the Jinjiang Novel "Sniper Butterfly" by author Qibaosu)
(مقتبس من رواية جينجيانج "الفراشة القناصة" للمؤلف تشيباوسو)
=Episode 1=
=الحلقة 1=
(Shengcan Culture)
(ثقافة شينغكان)
- Morning, Jin. - Morning.
- صباح الخير، جين. - صباح الخير.
Jin.
إحساس.
The people from Tongchen are already here.
إن الناس من تونغتشين موجودون هنا بالفعل.
Ms. Shen has gone in.
لقد دخلت السيدة شين.
Okay.
تمام.
- Morning, Jin. - Morning.
- صباح الخير، جين. - صباح الخير.
Jin, your coffee.
جين، قهوتك.
You're here. Hurry.
أنت هنا، أسرع.
Let me introduce you quickly.
دعني أقدمك بسرعة.
This is Tongchen Technology's tech partner,
هذا هو الشريك التقني لشركة Tongchen Technology،
Mr. Li.
السيد لي.
He's also a recently returned
لقد عاد مؤخرا أيضا
rising star in tech.
نجم صاعد في مجال التكنولوجيا.
And this is my Creative Director,
وهذا هو مديري الإبداعي،
and also my partner,
وشريكتي أيضًا
Ms. Cen.
السيدة سين
Hello, I'm Cen Jin.
مرحبًا، أنا سين جين.
Li Wu.
لي وو.
Wu, as in mist.
وو، كما في الضباب.
Let's begin directly.
لنبدأ مباشرة.
Okay.
تمام.
I'll give a brief overview first.
سأقدم نظرة عامة موجزة أولاً.
In this "Earth at the Critical Point"
في هذا "الأرض عند نقطة حرجة"
Environmental Art Exhibition,
معرض الفن البيئي
we want to start from the theme
نريد أن نبدأ من الموضوع
of "bond".
من "السند".
Exploring the bond between Earth and humanity,
استكشاف العلاقة بين الأرض والبشرية،
and the bond among all living things.
والرابطة بين جميع الكائنات الحية.
Humans and the natural world
البشر والعالم الطبيعي
are not isolated or separate.
ليست معزولة أو منفصلة.
Humans and mountains, rivers, seas,
البشر والجبال والأنهار والبحار،
plants and forests,
النباتات والغابات،
and all animals,
وكل الحيوانات،
we've always been part of nature.
لقد كنا دائمًا جزءًا من الطبيعة.
All living beings are interlinked
جميع الكائنات الحية مترابطة
and interdependent.
ومترابطة.
It's just that many times,
إنه مجرد عدد كبير من المرات،
we forget this connection.
لقد نسينا هذا الاتصال.
(Exhibition Highlights)
(أبرز ما في المعرض)
I went to the nearby mall
ذهبت إلى المركز التجاري القريب
and bought you a digital watch.
واشتريت لك ساعة رقمية.
That's all.
هذا كل شئ.
This is the core of our promo plan.
هذا هو جوهر خطتنا الترويجية.
As the proposal progresses,
مع تقدم الاقتراح،
we'll continue to add on,
سنستمر في الإضافة،
and refine the details.
وتحسين التفاصيل.
Thank you, everyone.
شكرا للجميع.
Sorry about that.
آسف على ذلك.
But I think this really suits him.
لكن أعتقد أن هذا يناسبه حقًا.
I'd like to ask,
أريد أن أسأل
what Ms. Cen mentioned
ما ذكرته السيدة سين
about the bond between humans and all beings...
عن الرابطة بين البشر وجميع الكائنات...
I'm wondering
انا اتساءل
if just a few images would be enough
إذا كان عدد قليل من الصور سيكون كافيا
to clearly convey the concept
لنقل المفهوم بوضوح
at our exhibition?
في معرضنا؟
We certainly can't rely solely
نحن بالتأكيد لا نستطيع الاعتماد فقط
on a few images to convey
على بعض الصور لنقل
the deeper meaning of "bond".
المعنى الأعمق لكلمة "الرابطة".
At the exhibition,
في المعرض،
we'll have multi-media
سيكون لدينا الوسائط المتعددة
presentations,
العروض التقديمية،
interactive experiences,
تجارب تفاعلية،
as well as physical exhibits
بالإضافة إلى المعروضات المادية
and other formats,
وغيرها من التنسيقات،
working together
العمل معًا
to build the rich meaning
لبناء المعنى الغني
of the theme "bond".
حول موضوع "السندات".
So visitors can understand
حتى يتمكن الزوار من الفهم
the deeper significance behind it.
الأهمية العميقة وراء ذلك.
Ms. Cen, how do you view
السيدة سين، كيف تنظرين إلى
the meaning of the word "bond"?
ما معنى كلمة "بوند"؟
To me, a bond
بالنسبة لي، سند
is the connection and entanglement between lives.
هو الاتصال والتشابك بين الأرواح.
It's something you can't cut off,
إنه شيء لا يمكنك قطعه،
a responsibility and a tie.
مسؤولية وربطة عنق.
Like a kite held by a string.
مثل طائرة ورقية ممسوكة بخيط.
Even if the wind blows it far away,
حتى لو هبت الرياح بعيدا،
you won't worry
لن تقلق
that it'll lose its direction or fall.
أنها ستفقد اتجاهها أو تسقط.
As long as the string is unbroken,
ما دام الخيط غير منقطع،
the bond will continue to exist.
الرابطة سوف تستمر في الوجود.
Of course,
بالطبع،
a bond isn't limited
السند ليس محدودا
to emotional ties between people.
إلى الروابط العاطفية بين الناس.
So...
لذا...
So, does that mean for you, Ms. Cen,
فهل هذا يعني بالنسبة لك، سيدتي سين،
that if this string is cut,
أنه إذا تم قطع هذا الخيط،
whether by storms or by someone's hand,
سواء بالعواصف أو بيد شخص ما،
all the ties within it
كل الروابط الموجودة بداخله
will completely disappear?
سوف تختفي تماما؟
Then, for something intangible, like feelings,
ثم بالنسبة لشيء غير ملموس، مثل المشاعر،
how would you determine
كيف يمكنك تحديد ذلك؟
whether it exists?
هل هو موجود؟
It's alright.
لا بأس.
I was just asking
كنت اسأل فقط
a small question of my own.
سؤال صغير خاص بي.
You don't have to rush
لا داعي للتسرع
to answer me, Ms. Cen.
للإجابة عليّ، السيدة سين.
Going forward, Tongchen and Shengcan
المضي قدما، تونغتشين وشينغكان
will have a long period of cooperation.
سيكون لدينا فترة طويلة من التعاون.
I hope that through
آمل أن من خلال
our joint efforts,
جهودنا المشتركة،
we can interpret the word "bond"
يمكننا تفسير كلمة "رابطة"
in a better,
في وضع أفضل،
deeper way.
طريق أعمق.
Thank you in advance, Mr. Li.
شكرا لك مقدما، السيد لي.
Li.
الذي - التي.
Not here?
ليس هنا؟
Li, where's your grandson?
لي، أين حفيدك؟
Li.
الذي - التي.
Alright, thanks.
حسنا، شكرا لك.
I'm not thirsty.
أنا لست عطشانًا.
Yan.
نعم.
Okay.
تمام.
You're called Li Wu, right?
اسمك لي وو، أليس كذلك؟
We're here to help you.
نحن هنا لمساعدتك.
Sit.
يجلس.
Li Wu.
لي وو.
This is Mr. Wu.
هذا هو السيد وو.
This is Ms. Cen.
هذه هي السيدة سين.
Ms. Cen
السيدة سين
is actually Mr. Cen's daughter.
هي في الواقع ابنة السيد سين.
The two of them
الاثنان منهم
came all the way from Yi City
لقد جاء كل الطريق من مدينة يي
just for this.
فقط لهذا.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Very polite, too.
مهذب جداً أيضاً.
Good grades as well.
درجات جيدة أيضاً.
Top of the class every year.
الأول على الفصل كل عام.
Show them off a bit, won't you?
أظهرهم قليلاً، أليس كذلك؟
No need.
لا حاجة.
It's really
إنه حقا
hot here.
حار هنا.
Though the air is good.
على الرغم من أن الهواء جيد.
Hey.
يا.
Where are you?
أين أنت؟
I'm in the restroom.
أنا في الحمام.
What about the Tongchen people?
ماذا عن شعب تونغتشين؟
I just saw them off.
لقد رأيتهم للتو.
Seems like they're
يبدو أنهم
pretty satisfied with the plan.
راضٍ جدًا عن الخطة.
Do you have plans for tonight?
هل لديك خطط لهذه الليلة؟
If not,
إذا لم يكن كذلك،
I thought we could
اعتقدت أننا نستطيع
treat them to dinner tonight.
ادعوهم لتناول العشاء الليلة.
Try to finalize the contract as soon as possible.
حاول الانتهاء من العقد في أقرب وقت ممكن.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Do you really understand what a "bond" is?
هل تفهم حقًا ما هو "السند"؟
Love is,
الحب هو
hate is too.
الكراهية أيضا.
But ignoring it is not.
ولكن تجاهله ليس كذلك.
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
you never contacted me once.
لم تتصل بي مطلقا.
Sorry. I couldn't make it to the afternoon meeting on time.
عذراً، لم أتمكن من الحضور إلى اجتماع بعد الظهر في الوقت المحدد.
Let me first make a toast to everyone.
اسمحوا لي أولاً أن أقدم نخبًا للجميع.
Thanks, Mr. Cheng.
شكرا لك السيد تشنغ.
You must be starving.
لا بد أنك جائع.
Dig in.
احفر في.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
This yellow croaker with rice cake
هذا السمك الأصفر مع كعكة الأرز
is the signature dish here.
هو الطبق المميز هنا.
Normally, you can't get it unless you reserve.
عادةً، لا يمكنك الحصول عليه إلا إذا قمت بالحجز.
Try it quickly.
جربها بسرعة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
This goose liver lotus root sandwich is also famous.
هذه الساندويتش من جذر اللوتس المصنوع من كبد الإوز مشهورة أيضًا.
Yes.
نعم.
This one's delicious too.
وهذا لذيذ أيضاً.
Ms. Shen,
السيدة شين،
so for our next project,
لذا بالنسبة لمشروعنا القادم،
will you be the one coordinating with us?
هل ستكون أنت الشخص الذي ينسق معنا؟
For a big project like Tongchen,
بالنسبة لمشروع كبير مثل تونغشين،
everyone in our company will definitely be involved.
الجميع في شركتنا سوف يشاركون بالتأكيد.
But it will be Ms. Cen
لكنها ستكون السيدة سين
who takes full responsibility.
من يتحمل المسؤولية كاملة؟
Full control.
السيطرة الكاملة.
Don't be fooled by Ms. Cen's young age.
لا تنخدع بصغر سن السيدة سين.
She is very capable.
إنها قادرة جدًا.
Previously, for the Bingdian Technology promotions,
في السابق، بالنسبة لعروض Bingdian Technology،
did you pay attention to them?
هل انتبهت لهم؟
That was fully managed
لقد تم إدارتها بالكامل
by Ms. Cen.
بقلم السيدة سين
That's perfect.
هذا ممتاز.
We thank you in advance.
نشكركم مقدما.
This is what we should do.
هذا ما يجب علينا فعله.
So should we...
فهل ينبغي لنا...
We will give 100% effort,
سنبذل جهدنا بنسبة 100%
striving to do our best.
نسعى جاهدين للقيام بأفضل ما في وسعنا.
Let's make a toast to the two of you.
دعونا نرفع نخبًا لكليكما.
- Here, thank you, Mr. Li. - Cheers to a good collaboration.
- حسنًا، شكرًا لك، السيد لي. - شكرًا على التعاون الجيد.
Thanks, Mr. Cheng.
شكرا لك السيد تشنغ.
- Cheers. - Thanks.
- شكرا.
You've been quiet
لقد كنت هادئا
all night.
طوال الليل.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
Ms. Shen.
السيدة شين.
Jin.
إحساس.
My friend came to pick me up,
لقد جاء صديقي ليأخذني،
so I'll head off first.
لذا سأتوجه أولا.
Okay.
تمام.
Bye.
الوداع.
Stay safe.
ابقى آمنًا.
Okay.
تمام.
I also called a driver.
اتصلت أيضًا بالسائق.
How are you leaving?
كيف ستغادر؟
I also booked a car.
لقد حجزت سيارة أيضًا.
Why didn't you ask Dr. Lu
لماذا لم تسأل الدكتور لو؟
to pick you up?
لالتقاطك؟
It's too late.
لقد فات الأوان.
What's late about it?
ما الجديد في هذا الأمر؟
You don't know how much
أنت لا تعرف كم
he loves opportunities like this.
إنه يحب الفرص مثل هذه.
My driver is here.
سائقي هنا.
I'll go first.
سأذهب أولا.
Okay.
تمام.
See you next time.
نراكم في المرة القادمة.
All right.
حسنًا.
Leaving.
مغادرة.
Ms. Cen Jin,
السيدة سين جين،
we'll leave first.
سنغادر أولا.
See you next time.
نراكم في المرة القادمة.
Bye.
الوداع.
You deliberately acted like you didn't know her
لقد تصرفت عمدا وكأنك لا تعرفها
and made me feel awkward.
وجعلني أشعر بالحرج.
No, I didn't.
لا، لم أفعل.
Still denying it?
هل لا تزال تنكر ذلك؟
Your face was stiff like plaster.
وجهك كان متيبسًا مثل الجبس.
Really, I didn't.
في الحقيقة، لم أفعل ذلك.
"Really, I didn't."
"حقا، لم أفعل ذلك."
Come on, stop lying to me.
تعال، توقف عن الكذب علي.
Today, you insisted
اليوم أصريت
on coming here, right?
عند مجيئك إلى هنا، أليس كذلك؟
Since you're here, be carefree.
بما أنك هنا، فلا داعي للقلق.
We'll still be collaborating later.
سوف نستمر في التعاون في وقت لاحق.
Du,
ل،
stop at the intersection ahead.
توقف عند التقاطع أمامك.
Okay.
تمام.
Alright, I won't say more.
حسنًا، لن أقول المزيد.
Ms. Shen created a work group.
أنشأت السيدة شين مجموعة عمل.
You should reply too.
ينبغي عليك الرد أيضاً.
(Ms. Shen: Thank you for your trust.)
(السيدة شين: شكرا لثقتكم.)
(Looking forward to a pleasant collaboration.)
(نتطلع إلى تعاون ممتع.)
(Zhang Xiaojiao: Win-win)
(تشانغ شياو جياو: الفوز)
(Moments)
(لحظات)
Lend me your phone.
أعطني هاتفك.
I'll return it later.
سأعود إليه لاحقًا.
(Good friends meeting)
(لقاء الأصدقاء الجيدين)
(Passion never cools)
(العاطفة لا تبرد أبدًا)
(Believe in yourself. You can become whoever you want to be.)
(ثق بنفسك. يمكنك أن تصبح من تريد أن تكون.)
(New experience: Today I'm an archer.)
(تجربة جديدة: اليوم أنا رامٍ.)
Who's that guy?
من هذا الرجل؟
Jin's boyfriend?
صديق جين؟
(Why didn't you call Dr. Lu to pick you up?)
(لماذا لم تتصل بالدكتور لو ليأخذك؟)
(You don't know)
(أنت لا تعرف)
(how much he loves opportunities like this.)
(كم يحب الفرص مثل هذه).
Done using my phone?
هل انتهيت من استخدام هاتفي؟
(Chun Chang: What's going on?)
(تشون تشانغ: ماذا يحدث؟)
(He's not really divorcing, right?)
(إنه لا يطلق حقًا، أليس كذلك؟)
(He's so heartless.)
(إنه قاسي القلب جدًا.)
(Ungrateful scum.)
(حثالة جاحدة)
Hey.
يا.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Is this Ms. Cen Jin?
هل هذه السيدة سين جين؟
May I ask who this is?
هل يمكنني أن أسأل من هذا؟
I'm Li Wu.
أنا لي وو.
Liwu?
صوت؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I'm a student from Yunfeng Village
أنا طالب من قرية يونفينج
who was sponsored by Mr. Cen before.
الذي كان برعاية السيد سين من قبل.
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Are you still there?
أنت لا تزال هناك؟
I'm here.
أنا هنا.
May I ask why you're contacting me?
هل يمكنني أن أسألك لماذا تتصل بي؟
Sorry to bother you.
آسف لإزعاجك.
Well...
حسنًا...
Last year,
في العام الماضي،
for some reason,
لسبب ما،
I couldn't take the college entrance exam.
لم أتمكن من اجتياز امتحان القبول بالجامعة.
I still want to continue studying.
لا أزال أريد مواصلة الدراسة.
Could you help me?
هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟
You didn't continue your studies?
لم تكمل دراستك؟
I remember the tuition was sent on time
أتذكر أن الدروس تم إرسالها في الوقت المحدد
to your grandfather's account.
إلى حساب جدك.
My grandfather passed away a year ago.
لقد توفي جدي منذ عام.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I'm living with my aunt now.
أنا أعيش مع خالتي الآن.
(Banling) Last year, my uncle told me our family
(بانلينج) في العام الماضي، أخبرني عمي أن عائلتنا
was struggling.
كان يكافح.
Around the time of the exam,
في وقت الامتحان تقريبًا،
he pulled me out to work.
لقد سحبني إلى العمل.
So, I completely missed the exam.
لذا، لقد فاتني الامتحان تمامًا.
This year, I want
هذا العام أريد
to resume studying.
لاستئناف الدراسة.
Go back to school.
العودة إلى المدرسة.
But...
لكن...
they wouldn't allow it.
لن يسمحوا بذلك.
I called Mr. Wu.
اتصلت بالسيد وو.
He told me to contact you.
لقد طلب مني أن أتواصل معك.
What does that mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
I don't know either.
انا أيضا لا اعرف.
But he said
ولكنه قال
that you two have separated.
أنكما انفصلتا.
So...
لذا...
he gave me your contact information.
لقد أعطاني معلومات الاتصال الخاصة بك.
Wait a moment.
انتظر لحظة.
I'll call him.
سأتصل به.
This is me
هذا أنا
using a borrowed phone.
استخدام هاتف مستعار.
Two minutes.
دقيقتان.
(Yiwen Creative Dream)
(حلم ييوين الإبداعي)
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
The kid from Shengzhou
الطفل من شينغتشو
called me.
اتصل بي.
You just pushed it onto me?
لقد دفعته للتو علي؟
This was started by your father.
لقد بدأ هذا بواسطة والدك.
How to decide
كيفية اتخاذ القرار
is also your family's matter.
وهي أيضًا مسألة تخص عائلتك.
Aren't you involved?
هل أنت غير متورط؟
We all are.
نحن جميعا كذلك.
So I leave the decision to you.
لذلك أترك القرار لك.
Of course.
بالطبع.
You can still be a good person.
لا يزال بإمكانك أن تكون شخصًا جيدًا.
After all, you've always been so noble.
بعد كل شيء، لقد كنت دائما نبيلًا جدًا.
This concerns a child's
هذا يتعلق بالطفل
life-altering matter.
مادة تغير الحياة.
How can you speak
كيف يمكنك التحدث
so lightly?
بهذه السهولة؟
Don't you find it cruel?
ألا تجد هذا قاسياً؟
You don't understand
أنت لا تفهم
these kinds of kids.
هؤلاء الاطفال.
But I've seen many.
ولكنني رأيت الكثير.
Kids who voluntarily give up the exam to work.
الأطفال الذين يتخلون طواعية عن الامتحان من أجل العمل.
They want to earn money but find the work too hard.
إنهم يريدون كسب المال ولكنهم يجدون العمل صعبًا للغاية.
Now, in front of you,
الآن أمامك،
pitifully, wanting to go back to study for college.
للأسف، أريد العودة للدراسة في الكلية.
Wu Fu,
وو فو،
you don't have to speak so harshly.
لا داعي لأن تتحدث بهذه القسوة.
Not everyone lives as easily as you.
لا يعيش الجميع بسهولة مثلك.
Life isn't that simple for everyone.
الحياة ليست بهذه البساطة بالنسبة للجميع.
He wants to move forward,
يريد المضي قدما
so he must endure the hardships he faces.
لذلك يجب عليه أن يتحمل الصعوبات التي يواجهها.
If he can't persevere,
إذا لم يتمكن من المثابرة،
whose fault is it?
من المخطئ؟
Besides, I've seen
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، لقد رأيت
that contract.
هذا العقد.
Even if we don't manage it,
حتى لو لم نتمكن من ذلك،
someone else will take over.
شخص آخر سوف يتولى الأمر.
So, in your eyes,
لذا، في عينيك،
human relationships
العلاقات الإنسانية
are just contracts that can be terminated anytime?
هل هي مجرد عقود يمكن إنهاؤها في أي وقت؟
In your heart,
في قلبك
our relationship is the same thing, right?
علاقتنا هي نفس الشيء، أليس كذلك؟
Alright.
على ما يرام.
I don't want to argue with you.
لا أريد أن أجادل معك.
I'm still working. I'll hang up.
مازلت أعمل. سأغلق الهاتف.
Who are you looking for?
من تبحث عنه؟
Where is the boy who was using your phone just now?
أين الصبي الذي كان يستخدم هاتفك للتو؟
I've already left.
لقد غادرت بالفعل.
The car has arrived. I can't wait.
وصلت السيارة. لا أستطيع الانتظار.
It's fine now.
إنه بخير الآن.
(Shengzhou)
(شينغتشو)
(Yunfeng)
(يونفينج)
Sorry.
آسف.
(Yunfeng Village Party Committee)
(لجنة حزب قرية يونفينغ)
Excuse me, may I ask
عذرا هل يجوز لي أن أسأل
if Mr. Yan Changsheng is here?
إذا كان السيد يان تشانغشنغ هنا؟
You mean Mayor Yan?
هل تقصد رئيس البلدية يان؟
He's already been promoted to mayor?
لقد تمت ترقيته بالفعل إلى عمدة؟
Right, I'm looking for him.
حسنا، أنا أبحث عنه.
He hasn't been in charge
لم يكن مسؤولا
of work in our village
من العمل في قريتنا
since last year.
منذ العام الماضي.
No problem.
لا مشكلة.
I'm just a reserve cadre in this village.
أنا مجرد كادر احتياطي في هذه القرية.
What do you need him for?
لماذا تحتاج إليه؟
I can help you register.
يمكنني مساعدتك في التسجيل.
Okay.
تمام.
Here's the situation.
وهنا الوضع.
I'm looking for a child.
أبحث عن طفل.
His name is Li Wu.
اسمه لي وو.
A couple of years ago,
منذ بضع سنوات،
when my father went to the countryside for research,
عندما ذهب والدي إلى الريف للبحث،
he learned about Li Wu's situation
لقد علم بحالة لي وو
and became his sponsor.
وأصبح راعيه.
I helped him with some procedures.
ساعدته في بعض الإجراءات.
I heard he recently
سمعت أنه مؤخرا
had some trouble,
واجهت بعض المشاكل،
so I came to check on him.
لذلك جئت للتحقق منه.
I know Li Wu.
انا اعرف لي وو.
Come, I'll take you there.
تعال، سآخذك إلى هناك.
May I ask your name?
هل يمكنني أن أسألك عن اسمك؟
My name is Cheng Lixue.
اسمي تشنغ ليكسو.
You can just call me Cheng.
يمكنك فقط الاتصال بي تشنغ.
Thank you, Ms. Cheng.
شكرا لك، السيدة تشنغ.
Slow down, the road is slippery.
أبطئ سرعتك، الطريق زلق.
Uncle.
عم.
Busy, huh?
مشغول، أليس كذلك؟
Turn ahead.
إتجه للأمام.
That's Li Wu's aunt's house.
هذا هو منزل عمة لي وو.
Uncle.
عم.
Busy, huh?
مشغول، أليس كذلك؟
After Li Wu's grandfather passed away,
بعد وفاة جد لي وو،
has he always lived
هل عاش دائما
with his aunt?
مع عمته؟
Yes, he lived there all along.
نعم لقد عاش هناك طيلة الوقت.
After missing the college exam,
بعد أن غاب عن امتحان الكلية،
he got his diploma
حصل على شهادته
and his uncle sent him to the mine
وأرسله عمه إلى المنجم
to work and earn money.
للعمل وكسب المال.
It's such a pity for this kid.
من المؤسف جدًا بالنسبة لهذا الطفل.
His grades were always excellent.
وكانت درجاته دائما ممتازة.
He's smart and hardworking,
إنه ذكي ومجتهد.
and kind-hearted.
و طيب القلب.
If it weren't for his uncle,
لو لم يكن عمه،
he would have already been admitted.
لقد تم قبوله بالفعل.
Such a bright future.
مستقبل مشرق حقا.
But our sponsorship funds
لكن أموال رعايتنا
were always transferred on time
تم نقلهم دائمًا في الوقت المحدد
to the bank card.
إلى بطاقة البنك.
The child is alone and helpless,
الطفل وحيد وعاجز.
so he needs relatives to take care of him.
لذلك فهو يحتاج إلى أقارب لرعايته.
Ahead, we're almost there.
أمامنا، نحن تقريبا هناك.
Run!
يجري!
Still running?
هل لا تزال تعمل؟
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Come here!
تعال الى هنا!
You scoundrel! You're looking for death!
أيها الوغد! أنت تبحث عن الموت!
You've been freeloading for so long.
لقد كنت تستغل الآخرين مجانًا لفترة طويلة.
Now you want to run?
الآن تريد الركض؟
It's not that easy!
ليس الأمر سهلا!
Don't hit him.
لا تضربه
Get lost!
اغرب عن وجهي!
Asking to get hit?
طلب الحصول على ضربة؟
They're always like this.
إنهم دائما هكذا.
Get lost!
اغرب عن وجهي!
Move aside!
تنحى جانبا!
Who let you run off?
من سمح لك بالهروب؟
It's fine.
إنه بخير.
I want to go.
أريد أن أذهب.
You can't stop me.
لا يمكنك ايقافي.
I'm not stopping you.
انا لا اوقفك
Secretary Cheng.
السكرتير تشنغ.
Aunt, what's going on with these two?
عمتي ماذا يحدث مع هذين الاثنين؟
- Nothing. - You're with me.
- لا شيء. - أنت معي.
- Educating the kid. - Eating my food. Give it back!
- تعليم الطفل. - أكل طعامي. أعيده!
Settle it all.
تسوية كل شيء.
Go wherever you want.
اذهب إلى أي مكان تريد.
All my wages from the mine
كل راتبي من المنجم
are with you.
معك.
Talking back, huh?
التحدث مرة أخرى، هاه؟
What? Want to hit me?
ماذا؟ تريد أن تضربني؟
Li Wu.
لي وو.
Uncle, what are you doing?
عمي ماذا تفعل؟
- Wu. - This kid won't listen.
- وو. - هذا الطفل لن يستمع.
Just teach him a lesson.
فقط علمه درسا.
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
Why don't you teach
لماذا لا تقوم بالتدريس؟
your own child like this?
طفلك مثل هذا؟
Who is she?
من هي؟
She's been helping
لقد كانت تساعد
the kids in our village study.
الأطفال في قريتنا يدرسون.
Mr. Cen's daughter.
ابنة السيد سين.
She came to see Li Wu.
لقد جاءت لرؤية لي وو.
Do you remember me?
هل تتذكرني؟
Yes, I remember.
نعم أتذكر.
Can I talk to him alone?
هل يمكنني التحدث معه على انفراد؟
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Wu, hurry.
وو، اسرع.
Your room.
غرفتك.
Come. Uncle, have a seat.
تعال يا عم، اجلس.
Hey, there's something on your mouth.
مهلا، هناك شيئا على فمك.
What's that?
ما هذا؟
A solar panel.
لوحة شمسية.
There's no electricity inside.
لا يوجد كهرباء بالداخل.
Did you make this yourself?
هل صنعت هذا بنفسك؟
You study here?
هل تدرس هنا؟
Can I take a look?
هل يمكنني أن ألقي نظرة؟
(High School Physics Olympiad Real Exam Questions)
( أسئلة الامتحان الحقيقي لأولمبياد الفيزياء في المرحلة الثانوية)
Last year's mock test?
اختبار تجريبي للعام الماضي؟
Do you still have
هل لا زال لديك
your grandfather's bank card?
بطاقة بنك جدك؟
It's with him?
إنه معه؟
Alright, don't eat anymore.
حسنًا، لا تأكل بعد الآن.
You go over there
تذهب إلى هناك
and sit.
و اجلس.
Let's eat the porridge together.
دعونا نأكل العصيدة معًا.
Secretary Cheng.
السكرتير تشنغ.
Have a seat.
خذ مقعدا.
Mom.
أم.
Ms. Cen, sit here.
السيدة سين، اجلس هنا.
Stop making noise.
توقف عن احداث الضوضاء.
Wu,
وو،
come eat.
تعال لتأكل.
Mom.
أم.
Wu.
وو.
I won't eat.
انا لن اكل
I'm here today for one thing.
أنا هنا اليوم لشيء واحد.
Why don't you let Li Wu go to college?
لماذا لا تدع لي وو يذهب إلى الكلية؟
You'll even complain, huh?
حتى أنك ستشتكي، أليس كذلك؟
Look at my situation.
انظر إلى حالتي.
Do I have money to send him to college?
هل لدي المال لإرساله إلى الكلية؟
His old man is dead.
لقد مات والده.
I'm the only labor left at home.
أنا العامل الوحيد المتبقي في المنزل.
Secretary Cheng knows that.
السكرتير تشنغ يعرف ذلك.
Do you think money falls from the sky?
هل تعتقد أن المال ينزل من السماء؟
So many mouths to feed at home.
هناك الكثير من الأفواه التي يجب إطعامها في المنزل.
He's already graduated from high school.
لقد تخرج بالفعل من المدرسة الثانوية.
You want me to work my life away
تريدني أن أعمل حياتي بعيدا
to send him to college?
لإرساله إلى الكلية؟
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
As far as I know,
بقدر ما أعرف،
Li Wu's grandfather's inheritance
ميراث جد لي وو
is all in your hands.
كل شيء بين يديك.
Nonsense inheritance.
ميراث هراء.
Those two broken houses of his
هذين البيتين المهجورين له
aren't even enough
ليست كافية حتى
to pay for his funeral.
لدفع تكاليف جنازته.
Inheritance?
الميراث؟
If you let him continue studying,
إذا سمحت له بمواصلة الدراسة،
tuition for repeating a year,
رسوم دراسية لإعادة سنة دراسية،
including college tuition,
بما في ذلك الرسوم الدراسية الجامعية،
you won't have to worry.
لن تقلق.
He has a good foundation.
لقد كان لديه اساس جيد.
If he focuses on studying, he can definitely get in
إذا ركز على الدراسة، فإنه يستطيع بالتأكيد الدخول
to a good school.
إلى مدرسة جيدة.
The return for you in the future
العائد لك في المستقبل
will only be more, not less.
سيكون فقط أكثر، وليس أقل.
I can't wait.
لا استطيع الانتظار.
The sooner he earns, the better.
كلما حصل على المال مبكرا، كان ذلك أفضل.
He's already an adult.
لقد أصبح بالغًا بالفعل.
Please respect his wishes.
من فضلك احترم رغباته.
You don't need to tell me this.
لا داعي لأن تخبرني بهذا.
He lives here with me.
إنه يعيش هنا معي.
Eats my food, and drinks my drinks.
يأكل طعامي ويشرب مشروباتي.
He has to help earn money.
عليه أن يساعد في كسب المال.
If I let him work,
إذا سمحت له بالعمل،
he goes to work.
يذهب إلى العمل.
Don't think that having a backer
لا أعتقد أن وجود داعم
changes anything.
يغير أي شيء.
College?
كلية؟
Don't even think about it.
لا تفكر حتى في هذا الأمر.
You're not meant to.
لا ينبغي لك ذلك.
Secretary Cheng.
السكرتير تشنغ.
I'm going out for some air.
سأخرج لأخذ بعض الهواء.
Uncle,
عم،
let's reconsider.
دعونا نعيد النظر.
There's someone sponsoring the kid's studies.
هناك شخص يرعى دراسة الطفل.
In the future, when he's successful,
في المستقبل، عندما ينجح،
he can earn more.
يمكنه أن يكسب المزيد.
Let's think about it again, alright?
دعونا نفكر في الأمر مرة أخرى، حسنًا؟
No need to consider.
لا داعي للتفكير.
Ms. Cen.
السيدة سين
Relationships in this village,
العلاقات في هذه القرية،
can be simple if you say so,
يمكن أن يكون الأمر بسيطًا إذا قلت ذلك،
or complicated if you say so.
أو معقدة إذا قلت ذلك.
But in the end,
ولكن في النهاية،
they are family.
إنهم عائلة.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
It's been raining a lot lately. They are also fixing roads here.
لقد هطلت الأمطار بغزارة مؤخرًا. كما أنهم يُصلحون الطرق هنا.
It's unsafe to walk at night.
من غير الآمن المشي في الليل.
I'll take you to have a meal first,
سأأخذك لتناول وجبة طعام أولاً،
and you can stay here for a night. You can leave tomorrow.
ويمكنك البقاء هنا لليلة واحدة. يمكنك المغادرة غدًا.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Watch your step.
انتبه لخطواتك.
This is the place where our village teacher
هذا هو المكان الذي يوجد فيه معلم قريتنا
is staying for the time being.
سيبقى في الوقت الراهن.
I've already had someone clean up.
لقد قمت بالفعل بتعيين شخص ما للتنظيف.
There's hot water in this thermos.
يوجد ماء ساخن في هذا الترمس.
See if you need anything else.
انظر إذا كنت بحاجة إلى أي شيء آخر.
You can call me.
يمكنك الاتصال بي.
Okay, thank you.
حسنًا، شكرًا لك.
Alright, then rest early.
حسنًا، إذن استرح مبكرًا.
I'm heading back to the committee.
أنا متجه إلى اللجنة مرة أخرى.
Okay, good night.
حسنًا، ليلة سعيدة.
(Flashlight)
(مصباح يدوي)
(Wu Fu, Divorce Agreement)
(وو فو، اتفاقية الطلاق)
(Wu Fu)
(وو فو)
(Divorce Agreement)
(اتفاقية الطلاق)
(I've drafted the agreement.)
(لقد قمت بصياغة الاتفاقية.)
(Take a look first.)
(ألق نظرة أولا.)
Who is it?
من هذا؟
It's me.
هذا أنا.
Li Wu.
لي وو.
There are many mosquitoes in the countryside.
هناك الكثير من البعوض في الريف.
I went to the village shop
ذهبت إلى متجر القرية
and bought some things you might need.
واشتريت بعض الأشياء التي قد تحتاجها.
(Mosquito coils)
(لفائف البعوض)
The power is out.
لقد انقطعت الكهرباء.
I was worried it would be inconvenient for you.
لقد كنت قلقة من أن الأمر قد يكون غير مريح بالنسبة لك.
These will make things a bit easier.
وهذا سيجعل الأمور أسهل بعض الشيء.
Li Wu.
لي وو.
Come in. Let's talk.
تفضل بالدخول، دعنا نتحدث.
Why did you think of coming to me?
لماذا فكرت في المجيء إلي؟
I want to continue studying.
أريد أن أستمر في الدراسة.
Only with success in my studies
فقط مع النجاح في دراستي
can I have the chance to repay
هل يمكنني الحصول على فرصة السداد؟
those who treated me well.
الذين عاملوني بشكل جيد.
I don't want to give up.
لا أريد الاستسلام.
I want to leave this mountain.
أريد أن أترك هذا الجبل.
So...
لذا...
I want to try
أريد أن أحاول
every possibility.
كل الإحتمالات.
Then next,
ثم بعد ذلك،
what's your plan?
ما هي خطتك؟
I don't know either.
انا أيضا لا اعرف.
I just
انا فقط
want to give it a try.
أريد أن أجربه.
Do you believe in fate?
هل تؤمن بالقدر؟
If someone told you,
إذا قال لك أحد،
no matter what you do,
مهما فعلت،
you cannot change your fate,
لا يمكنك تغيير مصيرك،
would you believe it?
هل تصدق ذلك؟
No.
لا.
I don't believe it either.
أنا أيضا لا أصدق ذلك.
I only believe in myself.
أنا أؤمن بنفسي فقط.
As long as one doesn't give up on oneself,
طالما أن الإنسان لا يتخلى عن نفسه،
there's always a way to solve problems.
هناك دائما طريقة لحل المشاكل.
It's too late today.
لقد فات الأوان اليوم.
You should go back and rest.
ينبغي عليك العودة والراحة.
Okay.
تمام.
Then I'll go.
ثم سأذهب.
Be careful on the way.
كن حذرا في الطريق.
Your door has no latch.
بابك ليس له مزلاج.
It's okay.
لا بأس.
I'll block it with the table, and that will do.
سأقوم بحظره بالجدول، وهذا سوف يفعل.
♪Light declares a brand-new day♪
♪الضوء يعلن عن يوم جديد تمامًا♪
♪Yesterday's scenes♪
♪مشاهد الأمس♪
♪Begin to repeat again♪
♪ابدأ بالتكرار مرة أخرى♪
♪Saying good morning♪
♪قول صباح الخير♪
♪Stars accompany the night♪
♪النجوم ترافق الليل♪
♪Countless sleepless times♪
♪عدد لا يحصى من المرات التي لم أنم فيها♪
♪Your "good night"♪
♪تصبحون على خير♪
♪Calms all my unease♪
♪يهدئ كل قلقي♪
♪The wind seems to have fallen♪
♪يبدو أن الرياح قد هدأت♪
♪Flowers bloom with smiling faces♪
♪تزهر الزهور مع الوجوه المبتسمة♪
♪Butterflies linger♪
♪الفراشات تبقى♪
♪So romantic♪
♪رومانسي جدا♪
♪Without noticing♪
♪دون أن يلاحظ♪
♪I found where my heartbeat began♪
♪لقد وجدت حيث بدأ نبض قلبي♪
♪It started long ago♪
♪لقد بدأ منذ زمن طويل♪
♪Sorry I arrived late♪
♪آسف لقد وصلت متأخرًا♪
♪I'm used to having your morning greetings♪
♪أنا معتاد على تلقي تحياتك الصباحية♪
♪Turning all hardships♪
♪تحويل كل الصعوبات♪
♪Into the simplest things♪
♪في أبسط الأشياء♪
♪I'm used to having your good nights♪
♪أنا معتاد على أن أحظى بليلة سعيدة مثلك♪
♪Afraid life is too short♪
♪أخشى أن الحياة قصيرة جدًا♪
♪Gone in the blink of an eye♪
♪رحل في غمضة عين♪
♪What should I do♪
♪ماذا يجب أن أفعل♪
♪Loving every good morning and good night with you♪
♪أحب كل صباح ومساء جيد معك♪
♪Writing our days♪
♪كتابة أيامنا♪
♪Into great little ordinary moments♪
♪إلى لحظات صغيرة عادية عظيمة♪
♪Maybe sometimes we'll drift apart♪
♪ربما نبتعد عن بعضنا في بعض الأحيان♪
♪Remember to come home on time♪
♪تذكر أن تعود إلى المنزل في الوقت المحدد♪
♪I made your favorite♪
♪لقد صنعت المفضل لديك♪
♪Dinner♪
♪العشاء♪